One of the biggest things that I see
that business owners do and they get
wrong is they burn themselves out trying
to build their business. They work way
harder than they need to, way more hours
than they need to to get stuff done. And
what I found is is that in business,
there's so many different nuances and
obstacles and things that we have to get
right that the problem is that when we
focus so much on doing all those things
right, we end up not doing them at all
because we're so focused on making sure
that we're getting everything right. And
so, let me explain this. That's what I
believe causes burnout is this need to
do everything right.
Instead, if you can literally program
your brain to go with the flow when
you're building your business, I want
you to think of it like a vacation
mindset. The mindset that you go on when
you're on a vacation. This is actually
how I actually came to the idea of
explaining this was I went on a Disney
cruise recently and I remembered the
mindset that I was in in a new place in
a new environment in a new experience.
This is something that we often do all
the time as people even when we're
driving a car or doing something like
that. My car is self-driving me right
now. That's why my hands are down on the
steering wheel. But [laughter]
when when we are doing something that we
don't have the time to pause and think
and adjust and like okay white knuckle
it and walk on eggshells so carefully to
make sure that we do everything
perfectly. See this is how we do
[clears throat] a lot of stuff in our
life. When I'm raising my kids, when I
am being a father to my kids, I don't
have time to walk on eggshells
through every part of my day with my
kids or they're going to get hurt that
things are going to happen that I don't
want to happen. I need to be able to be
aware of my surroundings, but then go
with the flow and adjust quickly without
having to make sure that I'm doing
everything perfectly. that mindset.
Again, like I said, when we go on a
vacation, we think of it that way
because we're going with the flow in a
new place, a new environment. We're
letting loose things like that. That
same mindset, if you can apply it in
your business,
will allow you to not burn yourself out.
And then what you want to do is you want
to take it a step further. You don't
overcommit.
You don't go into it with FOMO, fear of
missing out. I'm afraid of missing out
on an opportunity. I'm afraid of not
getting the kind of cash flow that I
want because I got to get this
opportunity right here. I got to make
sure that I take advantage of this over
here. And you overwork yourself. And so
those two things right there combined
where we're trying to make sure we do
everything perfectly. We're walking on
eggshells.
Combined with this idea of I got to make
sure that I do everything. I can't I
can't mess anything up. I can't I can't
um you know have fun. I have to make
sure that I say yes to everything, all
these opportunities or I'm going to miss
out.
That creates burnout. The overcommitment
and then we look at our life and we say,
"Okay, do I have boundaries? Do I have
the right boundaries over things? Am I
saying no to the stuff that is not
moving the needle forward for me in my
life that I'm looking at?" You know,
trading stocks has been something that
I've been doing recently. I've had a lot
of success with it. I been making
between 10 and $20,000 a month trading
stocks, which is amazing. But I did some
analysis. If I trade stocks in the
afternoon, I end up losing money or
breaking even. And it's a complete waste
of my time. Spread across a couple of
months. I actually did some AI analysis
where I had to analyze all of my trades
and it and we noticed that all of my
trades in the late afternoon either lose
money or break even. And so it
calculated and this was the the kicker.
It calculated that I lost $10,000
in the late afternoon session.
And I was like, wait, what?
But I was making like over 20,000 in the
morning session. And that's why I had
made 10,000 that month. That literally
if I had just not traded the afternoon
session, if I had eliminated what I
thought, oh, I don't want to miss out on
this opportunity, this opportunity to
trade. And it's sneaky because like I'll
make some money and then I'll lose it.
And I thought I was like breaking even,
but no, it was like on average,
Jeremiah, you're losing $10,000 in the
evening session and you're but you're
making 20,000 in the morning session.
Well, like what if you only trade in the
mornings?
Duh. And so like I've I've been doing
that and I'm like, "Oh my gosh, this is
amazing because now I'm actually making
money and not losing it." That's a
perfect example of what I'm saying is in
our businesses, we have this fear of
missing out, but we also might have
obligations, friends, family, church,
things like this that we feel like we
have to do.
We have to make sure of. I have very few
obligations I have to do. I have my
business and I have to take care of my
family, my my my in my home family.
Everybody else comes secondary to that.
I schedule time with my mom in I
schedule time with my siblings. I make
sure that time that I have at church,
I'm not overcommitting to stuff at
church and things like that simply
because I want to do this stuff. And I
want you to take a look at your life,
analyze it, take stock of what are you
choosing to do every single day? Where
are you choosing to put your energy and
your time and your focus? And is it
really
helping move the needle forward for the
life that you're designing? And that's
really the ultimate big picture of this.
What is the life that you are designing
for yourself, for your family that you
wish to create to produce the results
that you desire? What is the things that
you are putting together to structure
and design and create that dream life
that you have for you and your family?
And is it moving those things forward?
So imagine those things. I want you to
get a vision for the life that you're
creating for you and your family. I want
you to get a very clear vision on how
all of these pieces fit together. And
then I want you to take a look at what
are the things are they moving that
vision forward or are they holding you
back.
Take an analysis of that and start to
eliminate the stuff that is not moving
the needle forward for you in that
vision that you have for your life and
your family. I knew for me trading
stocks was a big part of that and I've
literally developed the skill over the
last 5 years to be able to now make
multiple six figures a month trading
stocks. It's incredible the the like the
the shift in that for me. It creates
cash flow it it for my business, more
extra money for my family. We're able to
do more. We're able to accomplish more.
I'm able to literally say no and say yes
to things that I want to simply because
I'm choosing to do those things. And
what I've been able to do is literally
design the exact life that we want for
my my family by envisioning it first.
the house we moved into the the even the
idea of having this car right here, this
self-driving car was something that I
envisioned and I would use it to be able
to record videos like this with you
guys.
And so I just I think it's amazing is is
that when you imagine your life and you
start to eliminate all the stuff that is
not moving that life forward for you,
you will start to see your life come
together in the ways that you never
imagined, the ways that you always
wanted. Listen, if you're a coach, if
you're a mentor, if you're a trainer, if
you're a consultant or a service
provider, and you want to know how to
get more clients online, I want to work
with you and show you how to do that. In
my wealthy coach academy program, I walk
people through step by step every single
week on how to do that, what to do, how
to make it work for them, and how to get
results. And I'd love to show you
exactly what to do as well. Jump in,
click one of the links in the
description below, and I'll see you in
there. We'll talk soon.